### Contact

artur.ampilogov@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/arturampilogov (LinkedIn) www.artur-ampilogov.com/ (Portfolio)

## Top Skills

Machine Learning
Open Al
Prompt Engineering

### Languages

English (Professional Working)

German (Elementary)

Spanish (Elementary)

Russian (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

IBM - Introduction to NoSQL Databases

University of Michigan - Python for Everybody

MCTS: .NET Framework 4, Windows Applications

EPFL - Functional Programming in Scala

# **Artur Ampilogov**

CTO | Freelance Lead Engineer | Remote Europe and US East Cost Yerevan, Armenia

## Summary

Over 15 years in the Information Technology area, including managing teams as CTO, Chief Architect, Lead software developer. Strongest technical skills: DevOps, Cloud Architecture (GCP, AWS, Azure, Yandex), AI/ML, React JS, Node JS,

TypeScript, C# .NET, Databases. Technical polyglot: worked with many languages and technologies.

# Experience

Socionom

Chief Technology Officer

January 2021 - Present (2 years 11 months)

St Petersburg, St Petersburg City, Russia

I helped a former colleague to build the educational social network.

Leading the technical team, interviewed and searched for candidates. Setup Atlassian Jira and managed technical tasks.

Updated the architecture to use a Cloud platform with microservices and Docker Swarm.

Developed Node JS microservices (Video converter, Auth, Zoom services). Set up auto delivery infrastructure with Terraform, Continuous Integration with Github and Git submodules. Created Dev, UAT and Production environments in the Cloud.

Provided documentation and technical plans for the product growth.

The cost of infrastructure and third party services was reduced in 5 times, it saved 30,000 USD per year.

Nodia

Senior Full Stack Engineer October 2023 - November 2023 (2 months) Building the web application for the Germany Web3/NFT startup and arts exhibitions. The project is built with the latest technologies: Next.JS v.14 App router, TypeScript, Tailwind, Firebase and Turso SQL DB.

Perci Health
Full-stack Developer (Part time)
July 2021 - October 2023 (2 years 4 months)
Armenia

Created new web applications to support the UK Health startup that helps fighting cancer.

Improved applications quality by covering new and old applications with E2E tests (Cypress and Microsoft Playwright). Simplified code base by moving the solutions to monorepo using Turborepo. Integrated many third party services. Micro-projects are implemented with the low cost infrastructure using Google Firebase.

#### Kana

Software Engineering Tech Lead January 2022 - September 2022 (9 months) Armenia

Helped the UK startup to implement Pricing SaaS product in a very challenging and dynamic work flow.

The web application is built with rich UI (Next.JS, Chakra UI) and multiple backend services (GraphQL, REST API, Queues, Relational and Document databases, Clickhouse DB). Simplified development cycle by moving the code base to Monorepo with Turborepo, using Docker Compose and Github CI Workflows. Provided deep integration with Stripe Billing provider, and many other third party services. Created a couple of public NPM packages for the main product usage (client and server side). Improved latency for high-load client requests by adding a small backend server written in Go lang.

Aurea Software 2 years 6 months

Product Chief Architect
September 2018 - April 2020 (1 year 8 months)

Initially joined the organization as the C# .NET Chief Architect. Then has changed the position to the Product Chief Architect, which was the key technical role for a large Supply Chain software.

It required to be a core person that other teams were dependent on to improve the product.

Crated tasks and provided code reviews for the Software development team, wrote E2E tests, reviewed the work of the manual QA team, created tasks and provided code review for the Auto QA team, created architecture documentation, implemented DevOps role in the cloud infrastructures (AWS and Azure).

Prepared technical reports during Due Diligence process in the middle of acquiring multiple companies.

A broad range of technologies in the Microsoft stack: C#, ASP.NET, ASP.NET Core, Entity Framework, MS SQL Server, xUnit tests, nUnit tests, Azure CI Deploy, AWS Cloud hosting, and many more.

Reduced the infrastructure cost by several thousands of USD per month after finding dozens forgotten virtual machines that were created by the migration team in the custom cloud.

C# .NET Chief Architect November 2017 - August 2018 (10 months)

Implemented new features for multiple projects, including creation of a product installer on Windows OS.

Full-stack role with multiple technologies: C#.NET, WPF, WiX installer, ASP.NET, ASP.NET Core, REST API, Angular.JS, TypeScript.

Sensing Cloud SpA
Full-stack Developer
January 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 10 months)
St Petersburg, St Petersburg City, Russia

Created web applications for Chilean startups, and a website for the non profit project to prevent Chilean forest fires.

Full stack role with variable technologies: AWS Lambda, Serverless, Node.JS, ReactJS, PHP, Jquery, Bootstrap, Shopify, MySQL, AWS DynamoDB.

Readify
Sustained Engineering Developer
June 2015 - December 2015 (7 months)

Melbourne, Australia

Improved and maintained applications for Australian clients with a variety of fields and technologies.

A mobile application for truck drivers (C#, XAML, Xamarin Native), a brand website of a mining corporation (C#, ASP.NET, MS SQL Server), an application for a large insurance company (C#, Microsoft Silverlight, WCF, MS SQL Server), multiple web sites created with TypeScript, React.JS, Angular.JS, Node.JS, AWS and Azure cloud hosting.

T-Systems International
Principal Software Developer
October 2012 - May 2015 (2 years 8 months)
Saint Petersburg, St Petersburg City, Russia

Created a brand new desktop application for the large Germany client in the automotive industry.

The role included work on the frontend (Windows Presentation Framework/ WPF, XAML), as well as on the backend (C# .NET services, WCF, MS SQL Server). The project was taken by almost 100 IT specialists seating in one building (software developers, DevOps, QA specialist, software architects, business analytics, designers, managers), it was one of the largest software teams in Europe working one project. The work included multiple business trips to Munich, Germany.

High Robotics
Technical Founder
July 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 6 months)
St Petersburg, St Petersburg City, Russia

With the goal to improve design and user experience in the IT industry opened the UK company called High Robotics LTD.

In collaboration with the hired designer developed new web applications for Chilean and Germany startups, as well improved User Experience for existing products.

One client intended to improve safety for mining workers by building a robot with wheels, camera and gas sensors. Our company made a research to design the best suited User Interface for a robot remote control. I programmed the realization in C#.NET and WPF. It was a real fun to play with a robot located in Chile across the globe.

To improve the software design created UI open sources projects: WPF/XAML controls with multiple style sets; SVG icon set compatible with Bootstrap.

Intourist - Thomas Cook
C# Developer
November 2010 - October 2012 (2 years)
St Petersburg, St Petersburg City, Russia

Automated bus tours scheduling and tourists tracking by creating a desktop application (Windows Forms, C#, MS SQL Server and ADO.NET).

Improved flight booking and tourists tracking for the Air tours department by creating a desktop application (C#, Windows Presentation Framework (WPF), MS SQL Server, LINQ and ADO.NET).

Supported and improved the existing insurance web site written in C# (ASP.NET, JQuery, CSS, WCF, MS SQL Server and Microsoft Reporting Services).

Saint Petersburg State Institute of Psychology and Social Work Software Engineer

March 2010 - October 2010 (8 months)

Saint Petersburg, St Petersburg City, Russia

Developed and supported IT projects for the Psychology institute. The main one included programming Microsoft Sharepoint MOSS 2007, an internal portal for digital workflows and document processing. It required a close collaboration with the dean and the head of IT department. Also extended the physical Ethernet network in a new building.

Saint Petersburg State University
Teacher of the IT course
September 2009 - July 2010 (11 months)
Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Provided the introductory IT course for the Psychology and the Social department students in the Saint Petersburg State University. The course included basic computer structure, creating websites with pure HTML and CSS, visualization of XML data and T-SQL queries.

Nevskie Shkafy Information Technology Specialist March 2008 - March 2010 (2 years 1 month) Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Software developer role.

Programming the internet shop for the large wardrobe company with PHP and MySQL database. Migrated visual wardrobe configuration in the website from Macromedia Flash to Microsoft Silverlight C#.

IT administrator and help desk manager roles.

Supported clients and colleagues with IT tasks, maintained the fleet of computers, hardware and software installation/updates, extended physical Ethernet network through the organization offices, set up routers, switches, network and Microsoft Windows servers.

Sales and courier role.

Supported internet shop clients with wardrobe selection, delivered paper contracts to clients.

SEO-promotion group Junior Software Engineer June 2007 - March 2008 (10 months) Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Search engine optimizations for the multiple clients, improving ranks for search results in Google and Yandex websites. Variety of stacks: PHP, ASP Classic.

## Education

Saint Petersburg State University

Master, Math, Information technologies · (2002 - 2008)